NETFLIX PRESENTS
Every time it 's " just a bit longer . "
You 've been working here three years .
Yeah , but we haven 't been paid for three months !
Those three years mean nothing , we 've forgotten them !
We want our three months ' pay !
We want our three months !
Don 't talk to him on the phone .
Make him give us our money !
That 's enough !
Earlier , on the site ,
I told you we were going to pay you today .
But we 've just heard Mr. N 'Diaye is away on business
and hasn 't left the money .
We don 't want to hear that .
Put that phone down and talk to us !
Cheikh , I 'm talking to you .
I don 't want a cozy chat . We 're here for our money !
I 'm talking to you as their leader .
Talk to everyone .
This concerns everyone .
There are four of us .
In this office we 're working , just like you .
Do you understand ?
What 's happening here isn 't our fault .
That may surprise you , but not me .
We 've gone three months without pay . Four now !
You know what ? Keep the money .
But remember that we have families .
I know .
He 's right .
Our fathers , mothers and brothers depend on us .
They 're the reason we work .
I 'm so in debt that I wait till 8 : 00 or 9 : 00 ...
I wait for it to get dark before I go home .
That 's not right .
That money is our due .
Souleiman !
Take the dress .
Ada , you 're still seeing that guy ?
Take the dress and go .
You 're just watching the ocean .
You 're not even looking at me .
You 're so beautiful .
Even more so today .
Don 't make fun of me .
It 's true !
You 're even more beautiful .
Because I haven 't seen you for three days ?
Yes , maybe .
You 're too beautiful .
I swear .
You 're a joker .
Me ?
Too bad if you don 't believe me .
Wait ...
What 's wrong ?
I heard footsteps .
Footsteps , here ?
It 's nothing .
There 's no one .
I heard someone .
What are you doing here ? Who are you ?
- What are you doing ? - Who are you ?
Get outta here !
Hey , calm down .
Don 't talk to us like that .
Don 't argue ! Out !
This isn 't a whorehouse !
What did you say ?
Get outta here !
Lucky for you ...
- Leave him , Souleiman , let 's go . - Get outta here !
What 's so funny ?
Did that guy annoy you that much ?
Anyone would get annoyed .
Here 's your bag . I 'm going .
- Is that why you 're laughing ? - Yes , that 's why .
Okay .
I 'm going . It 's late .
- Why so soon ? - I have to go .
You don 't do anything at home .
I have to go .
Wait a bit .
I have to go . It 's late .
It 'll be night soon . I 'll see you later .
Tonight ?
What 's wrong ?
I wanted to give you that .
It 's really nice . Thanks .
- I 'm going . - You 're the loveliest .
Why in such a hurry ? I wanted to tell you ...
Tell me what ? I have to get back . Tell me later .
Come here .
- Kiss me again . - Tsk .
Wait till tonight .
Wait till tonight !
I 'm going .
What is it ?
Nothing .
- Come for your bag ? - Yes .
Come here .
Take your bag . There it is .
Mariama .
Why the long face ?
Did you lose your virginity on the way ?
What did you do ?
Nothing , we just walked .
Ada .
You know you 're marrying Omar in ten days ?
Before God .
But I love Souleiman .
Don 't make me laugh !
You know what he wants ?
To sleep with you , then he 'll dump you !
Forget it , Mariama .
Ada , we 've been friends since we were little .
It 's my duty to tell you the truth .
Hanging out with those sluts has changed you .
Nonsense !
Keep this between us .
No one must know .
That 's all I 'm asking .
But ... don 't you get it ?
God is testing you .
He put Souleiman in your path
to test your commitment to Omar .
It 's obvious .
You must be blind not to see that !
Mariama , it 's okay , I 've got it .
But can we keep this between us ?
Okay , then .
But you 're asking a lot .
You 're crazy !
Go on !
Have you called Omar ?
No credits left .
Call him before he catches his plane .
Okay .
Call him , okay ?
Grandma ...
are you okay ?
Beep Omar so he 'll call you back .
Let 's see the dress .
Hello .
May God protect us .
Yes .
No .
Okay . Have a nice trip .
Is that how you talk to Omar , your husband-to-be ?
You shouldn 't talk like that to your husband .
How should I talk to him ?
You speak sweetly to a man .
" Darling , " " my love , "
" I miss you " ...
- " Sweetie . " - Right .
That 's good .
Otherwise , he 'll take a second wife before you 're pregnant .
Get it ?
Do you know how many other women would love to be in your place ?
Hold on to that place . Times are tough !
What did you expect ?
Ada , the boys have gone .
What ?
Out to sea .
Ada .
They went in a boat . Souleiman , Cheikh , all of them .
Abdou , my little brother ?
But Abdou doesn 't have a clue about the sea !
You know he can 't swim !
No , no !
I don 't believe it !
It 's too late . They 've already gone .
Please calm down .
Souleiman .
What also worries me
is that the club could go bust because of this .
No . Once the girls hear from the boys ,
they 'll be back here to dance .
Girls come here for the boys ,
not to dance alone in front of the mirror .
Let 's pray they get to Spain safe and sound .
Eat something , Ada .
Eat something or you 'll get sick .
Leave me alone .
You have to get a grip .
Don 't lose it now .
Ada .
Aren 't you listening ?
Get up !
Get up .
Ada , are you okay ?
I 'm okay .
- You 're all right ? - Yes .
Where 's your phone ? I couldn 't reach you .
I was sleeping .
Why don 't you come in through the door ?
Can 't we stand where we like ?
Don 't start ! Ada , come on , let 's go for a walk .
I don 't feel like it .
Come on , we 'll get some sea air . We won 't go far .
No , it 's okay .
Please .
Some old local fishermen
come back from fishing
with such a full net
that everyone follows them to see what they 've caught .
People rush forward , shouting that they 've caught a huge fish .
Children and the whole neighborhood come for a look .
But as they approach the net ,
it 's not a fish they see there ,
but Souleiman 's lifeless body .
Ada , come here !
Ada , come here ! What are you doing ?
I wasn 't sure about the color .
Thanks .
You 'll see , it 'll change your life .
Do you like it ?
Yes .
What 's the matter ?
Nothing .
You haven 't eaten .
I 'm not hungry .
We 're very happy on this great day .
And we praise the Lord
because it 's the day every parent wants .
Since Omar 's birth ,
his mother and I have hoped
to attend his wedding .
Ada , welcome .
This is now your home .
If you had had a brother ,
he would never have been
as welcome as you are in this house .
Only a woman in her nuptial veil .
The beauty of a woman
comes through marriage .
It is the will of God .
And it 's part of our tradition .
Such is the ritual of marriage , which is a divine blessing .
So let us praise the Lord .
I thank you all .
Imam , let us pray together .
Look at this room !
It 's gorgeous !
It 's really pretty .
May God protect you .
Ada , congratulations !
Thank you .
Ada , your bedroom is awesome !
I can 't believe it .
You 'd think that ...
I don 't know what to say .
All right , Fanta ...
No , but have you seen this room ?
I 'm never leaving here .
Omar can marry me , too .
I 've been seduced by the bedroom !
Everything is new .
Ada , let 's take a photo .
Leave me out of it .
- Come on ! - I don 't want to .
- Ada , come on . - Leave me alone .
Ada , come on !
Don 't keep nagging .
You show-off !
All right .
- Like this . - Look .
One last pose .
You 're really showing off .
You got the jackpot here .
The house is amazing .
We 'll post this one .
Ada , just one .
Didn 't you hear me ?
One more .
Tell Omar I want to be his second wife .
She doesn 't know her worth .
Those girls she hangs around with ...
Sluts !
Ada , I 'm talking to you .
Ada , why are you doing this to yourself ?
Look at me . If you can 't do this , let 's just leave .
When I advised you to marry Omar ,
it was so that you 'd enjoy it . Not for this .
It was for your happiness .
So you 'd be at peace .
In your own interest .
But look at you ...
Come on , let 's go if you can 't do it .
Are you crazy ?
You love money more than anything and you 're telling her to leave ?
To go where ? Have you seen this beautiful house ?
You witch ! It 's you telling her that ?
You 're crazy ! Don 't listen to her , she 's full of shit .
Fanta , if it was me ,
I 'd gobble up his cash without any scruples .
Let her do the same , then .
Have you seen her ? She can 't do it .
Where are you going , Ada ?
I 'll come with you .
But you should understand one thing .
Out there is one big struggle .
You 'll have no father or mother .
It 'll just be you , all on your own .
If you 'd rather face that reality
than stay in this house of happiness ,
then let 's leave .
Don 't tell me that Souleiman - -
Fanta !
Just look at her and think .
I 'll never love Omar .
Who says you have to ?
You have everything here .
Fanta , shut up a minute .
Look at her , if she 's your friend .
Omar is only here three months a year , the rest of the time in Italy .
You 're not thinking . He 'll hardly be here .
- We 'll have the house to ourselves ! - Shut up !
Ada , I have something to tell you .
Ada , come on .
Not now .
She has something to say .
- What ? - You 're not coming ?
I 've just seen Souleiman .
He ran away .
Souleiman ? What ?
- I saw him . - Why are you lying , Mariama ?
We saw him .
- Where ? - Ada , calm down .
You witch , stop lying !
I 'm not talking to you .
Did you hear that ?
Fire , fire !
You 'll have to make a statement .
It 's a formality , but it 's important .
Just a second .
- Issa . - Commissaire .
Are you okay ?
- Fine . - Are you sure ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
Because yesterday you collapsed and ...
No , it was nothing , I was just feeling faint .
Have you seen a doctor ?
I will , Commissaire , but everything is fine .
Are you sure ?
Inspector Issa Diop .
Our young star .
He 'll be investigating .
Mr. Niang , the owner of the property .
Pierre will give you the file .
Give it to Issa .
The witnesses all say pretty much the same thing .
Mr. Niang .
Are you going ? I 'll see you out .
Thank you .
Guys ...
Feeling better , Inspector ?
Yes , I 'm fine .
Gloves !
No breaking and entering ?
No , nothing was forced .
It 's weird , nothing sparked the fire .
Nothing sparked it ?
The mattress just spontaneously combusted ?
So the firemen said .
Hello , Madam . Are you Souleiman Fall 's mother ?
Police .
Is that him ?
What 's happened to my son ?
- Where is Souleiman ? - He went to sea a week ago .
He was seen last night at about 10 : 00 .
Where 's his room ?
My son ? Where was he seen ?
Who saw my son ? That 's impossible .
He went to sea .
Tell me where he was seen !
Who saw my son ?
- Sir ... - Madam .
Listen .
No , no ... Wait !
Calm down !
He 's wanted on a serious matter . Let me do my job .
Sir , you can 't search through my house like this !
Madam , let go of me . Where is his room ?
Where is Souleiman 's room ?
Look at me .
Look at me when I 'm talking to you .
Where is Souleiman Fall ?
I don 't know where he is .
Really ?
But you know him , don 't you ?
Slightly .
Only slightly ?
Look at me .
Do you know where you are ?
Yes .
Where ?
At the police station .
Do you know why ?
No .
Souleiman ...
is wanted
for arson .
And you 're helping him .
That 's a serious matter .
I don 't understand .
- You don 't understand ? - No .
You don 't know what he did ?
I don 't know what 's going on .
You know what you did ?
You were his accomplice
in setting fire to your wedding bed .
That 's impossible .
Really ?
Souleiman went to sea . He couldn 't have started a fire .
He went with the others in a boat .
A week ago . He 's either at sea or in Spain now .
You expect me to believe that ?
You 're lying !
No .
Out of you two , I believe Mariama .
She wasn 't the only one to see him .
Why do you believe Mariama ?
I 'm telling you the truth .
Youssef !
How many times have I told you about the aircon ?
I want it fixed by tomorrow !
Where 's Souleiman ?
I 'm telling you the truth . I don 't know where he is .
He went in a boat .
Stay here .
Inspector .
Are you okay ?
Send Ada Niang home . We 'll carry on tomorrow .
Who 's that ?
Who 's calling you ?
- Give me your phone ! - No , it 's mine !
Give it here !
Here ! If you 'd brought her up right , we wouldn 't be in this situation !
Dad , give it back . It 's no one .
These girls were badly brought up . It 's your fault !
They must have had good reason to question you .
If you 're involved in this , you 'll have me to answer to .
Fanta , drink this .
It 's sugar .
Fanta , what 's going on ?
You 're freezing .
What happened to you ?
I don 't know .
Where does it hurt ? Tell me .
It looks a lot worse than it is .
She just fainted .
When Mariama wakes up ,
give her two pills .
Then two tomorrow after her breakfast .
Oh , God !
Who are you ? What are you doing here ?
- Well ? - Where 's our money ?
- How did you get in ? - Who cares ? We 're in now .
Laye ...
what 's going on here ?
Who are they ?
He knows .
Yes , he does .
What the hell is this ? Who are you ?
We 'll refresh your memory .
Building 13 .
The tower site .
Give us our money !
Don 't fuck with me !
You know what ? Get outta here !
Our money .
Yes .
The 32 million that you owe us .
Four months ' wages .
I 'm calling the police . You hear me ?
Calm down , I 'll sort this out .
Here 's what we 'll do .
I 'm asking you to leave my property .
Understand ? Don 't make me lose my temper .
There 's no need for that .
We 've come to warn you .
We 'll be back . Thirty-two million , our wages .
Our money .
Give us our money !
Mum ...
Mum !
We 're going to the clinic .
Omar 's parents want you to take a virginity test .
A test ?
You leave us no choice .
Get up .
I 'm waiting .
Can I have my phone back ?
We 'll see .
I 'll wait outside .
Clench your fist .
Congratulations , Madam . Your daughter is a virgin .
- Thank you . - No problem .
Give me back my phone .
Don 't look at me like I took you to the devil .
My phone ! You got what you wanted .
Your father wanted this , not me .
Ada , come here ! Where are you going ?
Where are you going ?
- No , wait ! - It 's all right , let me go .
The marabout said
that a spirit got in through my belly button
because I don 't dress correctly .
The marabout is talking crap .
Something took hold of me last night .
Are you serious ?
You 've gone totally crazy .
Don 't believe me , then , I don 't care .
Hello , Ada ?
I 've called you four times !
What 's up with you ? I 'm at Fanta 's .
What 's the matter with you lot ?
We have to talk . Come to the fast-food place .
Not on the phone . Come now .
Look how gorgeous you are on that photo .
There were no spirits then !
You shouldn 't joke about it .
Just wait till it happens to you .
Me ? The spirits are scared of me !
Dior , swear you won 't tell anyone .
Don 't tell me you 're possessed by a spirit !
Never mind . Tell me .
Swear .
Swear , for real !
What do you want ?
Nothing for me .
A coffee .
Excuse me .
An espresso , please .
- What is it ? - Swear .
Swear to keep it to yourself .
I swear . Now you 've got me worried .
Souleiman is here .
What ?
Look at his message .
TONIGHT 3AM AT DIOR 'S SOULEIMAN
Seriously ?
What the hell is this ?
What do you mean ?
Ada , it 's the police !
The police ? I 've done nothing wrong .
Think about it .
They want to get you .
- Me ? - To trap you .
I 'll call to check .
Don 't bother . It 's Souleiman , I can feel it .
Dior ...
Hello .
Who 's that ?
You texted me last night . Who are you ?
I helped out a guy who wanted to send a message .
What did he look like ?
A young guy . I don 't know , he looked blind .
Blind ? Are you messing with me ?
Stop being paranoid . I 'm going .
- Ada , no ... - Give me your keys .
It 's a trap .
I 'm a big girl . Your keys !
Dior , I 'm a big girl .
Your keys !
Ada , you can 't be serious .
What would I do without you ?
Mrs. Niang .
- What 's going on ? - Dior , leave us .
Move along .
Let me talk to her .
Leave us .
- I 'm not done with you . - Don 't you get it ?
I don 't know where Souleiman is . You can 't follow me like this !
You don 't know the law .
Talk or you 'll make things worse for yourself .
- What do you want ? - Tell me where Souleiman is .
I 've already told you .
Souleiman went to sea .
No , he started the fire .
Look at me . Talk or I 'll lock you up .
You really want to know ?
It 's true , Souleiman was more than a friend .
That 's no revelation .
Now leave me alone .
Where are you going ? Let 's go .
Leave me alone !
- Let me out ! - Shut up !
Let me out ! I haven 't done anything !
Tell me what I 've done !
Don 't make me come over there .
I haven 't done anything .
What have I done ?
Yes , the boat comes from Kafountine ,
in Casamance .
Anyway ...
The survivors said something that might interest you .
You know there was a storm a few days ago .
Hello ?
They managed to stay afloat . They 're fishermen , they 're used to it .
But the next day , they ran into an overturned boat .
No sign of life anywhere near .
The boat might have been drifting for a while .
It was broken in half .
The chances of finding survivors are bleak .
Hello ?
I 'll call you back if anything comes up .
Bye , good luck .
Did you lock up the girl who 's shouting ?
Yes , I want her to talk .
What 's wrong with you ?
Her husband 's here . Let her go .
Ask me first next time !
I couldn 't reach you last night . Why ?
I felt ill again .
Have you seen a doctor ?
Yes , it 's nothing serious .
If it 's nothing , then be reachable 24 / 7 .
Right .
Some girls got into Mr. N 'Diaye 's place , asking for money .
- Girls ? - About ten of them .
Put a patrol there from 8 : 00 p.m. to 6 : 00 a.m. Got it ?
I don 't want to hear any more about this .
Were the girls there about the unpaid wages ?
What unpaid wages ? That 's not our problem .
They broke in , that 's all .
Sort it out . I want it to stop .
Mr. N 'Diaye has done a lot for us .
Now let the girl go .
My phone . And my bag .
Is this it ?
What is it ?
What are you doing ?
What 's wrong ?
Nothing .
Did they do something to you ?
- No , nothing . - So come on , let 's go .
What 's the problem ?
I 'm not coming with you .
Are you mad ? Did you bang your head ?
Stop it , come on .
Leave me alone , Omar .
I 'm not coming with you .
What 's going on ? What are you waiting for ?
What is this bullshit ?
What 's got into you ? Get in , I don 't have time for this .
Let me go !
Why are you shouting ?
- I 'll shout if I want . - I 'm your husband .
I 'm not your wife !
What ?
What ? We just got married and you 're not my wife ?
I don 't love you .
Let go of me !
She 's gone mad !
Where are you going ?
Have you gone mad ?
You know what ? Piss off !
You wouldn 't give me a hard-on , anyway !
She 's mad .
I want to sell my phone .
iPhone .
Two hundred thousand .
I 'll give you 150,000 .
No , 200,000 .
Is it yours ?
Yes , it was a present .
- I 'll give you 150,000 . - 200,000 .
- Is that your last word ? - Yes .
Do you want a replacement ?
That one .
Let 's discuss the price , then .
As soon as she wakes up ,
Mariama must plunge verses of the Quran
into a bowl of clean water ,
and then pour the holy water over her head .
That will instantly drive away the spirits .
Then , if your daughter behaves like a good Muslim ,
says her prayers five times a day and wears the veil ,
there 's no reason
for the spirits to come back to torment her .
God bless us all .
Thank you .
Thanks again . Have a pleasant evening .
Mariama ?
Watch carefully . You see this bit ?
You put it here ,
then turn it
and pull .
The other end is for opening soft drinks and beer .
Vodka and liqueurs go in the small glasses .
I hope you 're getting this .
Soft-drink glass , wine glass , spirit glass .
- Got it ? - Yes .
You have to remember it all .
How can you still believe it 's Souleiman ?
You shouldn 't go .
Where 's the money ?
We 'll wait for you tomorrow at 3 : 00 a.m. in the cemetery .
If you don 't have the money then ,
we 'll burn your tower down .
Where have you come from ?
I 'm talking to you !
Souleiman ?
Souleiman , is that you ?
Ada ...
Souleiman , it 's the police ! Run !
Ada .
Ada ... it 's me .
It 's me , Souleiman .
Dior !
- I saw ... - Ada .
- Tell me ! - The boys are back .
What ?
Ada , wait !
Fanta ?
Ada .
Souleiman told me about you in the boat .
You know ...
in your final moments ,
you unburden your heart .
He told me ...
that he regretted so much
not having said goodbye to you .
He couldn 't .
None of us could .
Ada .
Souleiman ...
You were the love of his life .
He wanted to come back for you .
And be yours .
It was about 5 : 00 a.m.
It was quiet in the boat .
As the sun was rising ,
the guys were quiet .
I thought we were nearly there
because I could see a mountain in the distance .
I thought we 'd reached Spain
and we 'd finally be able to call you all .
I shouted for joy .
Then it all happened so quickly .
A strong wind whipped up the sea .
We were terrified
by the power of the waves .
Some were shivering with fear .
Others were sobbing with distress .
What I 'd thought was a mountain
was a wave .
Immense .
It lifted up our boat , which collapsed like a building .
We were cast into the depths .
Chief !
The girl has gone .
MISSED CALLS COMMISSAIRE SY
You know what happened last night ? Another fire .
A fire is raging and you 're sleeping ?
At Mr. N 'Diaye 's . Again , nothing sparked it .
Commissaire , let me do the investigation .
Please .
Go ahead .
Thank you .
Twenty .
Twenty-two .
Twenty-four .
Twenty-six .
Twenty-eight .
Thirty .
Let me go . You have the money .
You 're going nowhere .
It 's your fault we 're dead . Never forget .
I 'm sorry .
" I 'm sorry . "
You have your money .
Thirty-two million .
It 's all there .
Let me go .
Not yet .
Dig our graves first .
Look , he doesn 't even know how to dig .
That 's real work !
Dig till your hands burn .
Faster !
Every time ...
you look at the top of the tower ,
you 'll think of our unburied bodies
at the bottom of the ocean .
I knew you 'd be back .
It could only be you .
I 'll always taste
the salt of your body in the sweat of mine .
How beautiful you are .
I saw you in the enormous wave which consumed us .
All I saw was your eyes and your tears .
I felt your weeping dragging me to the shore .
Your eyes never left me .
They were there , within me .
Pouring their light into the depths .
Fanta ?
Commissaire .
The case is closed .
Come on , girl !
Some memories are omens .
Last night will stay with me ,
to remind me who I am ...
and show me who I will become .
Ada , to whom the future belongs .
I am Ada .
Subtitle translation by Howard Bonsor